Art Seiden Papers
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Art Seiden Papers.
undated, 1950-1996
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Seiden, Art.
2 linear feet.
Children's illustrator residing in Woodmere, N.Y., has illustrated over 300 books.
MSS19980359
Biography
Published Works:
Author:
My ABC Book, Wonder Books, 1953.
Junior Joke Book, Wonder Books, 1955.
Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs, Treasure Books, 1955.
1-2-3-4-5-6-7, McLoughlin, 1958.
1-2-3: Pictures, McLoughlin Brothers, 1958.
Counting Rhymes, McLoughlin Bros., 1959.
Puppies, McLoughlin, 1962.
Kittens, McLoughlin, 1962.
Jack and the Beanstalk Art, Golden Press, 1964.
Tom Glazer's Treasury of Songs for Children, Songs Music, 1964.
Seiden's Book of Toys, McLoughlin Bros., 1965.
The Cub Book of Trucks, Lion Press, 1966.
The Cub Book of Trains, Lion Press, 1966.
Stories about Elves, Fairies, and Little People to Read Aloud, Wonder Books, 1969.
Everything on Wheels, Grosset, 1981.
One Nose, Ten Toes, Grosset & Dunlap, 1981.
Little Bunny Learns Colors, Random House, 1982.
Look on the Ground, Grosset & Dunlap, 1982.
Michael Shows Off Baltimore, Outdoor Books, 1982.
Tick-Tock, Grosset & Dunlap, 1982.
Trucks, Platt & Muck, 1983.
Baby Animals, Preschool Press, 1984.
Illustrator:
Margaret W. Brown,
Jean H. Berg, Three mice and a Rat, Wonder Books, 1950.
Alf Evers, The Little Engine that Laughed, Wonder Books, 1950.
Helen Fletcher, Things to Cook, Paxton-Slade, 1951.
Edward Kean, Howdy Doody and the Princess, Simon & Schuster, 1952.
Felix Sutton, The Big Treasure Book of Wheels: 70 Things that Move on Wheels, Grosset, 1953.
Carlo Collodi, Pinocchio, Wonder Books, 1954.
Mabel Watts, Where is the Keeper?, Western Publishing Co., 1954.
Edward Kean, Howdy Doody and His Magic Hat, Simon & Schuster, 1954.
Evelyn Andreas, Fairy Tales: The Big Treasure Book of Fairy Tales, Grosset & Dunlap, 1954.
Gertrude Crampton, Train Stories, Simon & Schuster, 1958.
Morris Schreiber, Stories of Gods and Heroes: Famous Myths and Legends of the World, Grosset & Dunlap, 1960.
Adelaide Holl, Listening for Sounds, Golden Book, 1963.
Gene Darby, Dinosauer Comes to Town, Whitman, 1963.
Dorothy Haas, Patrick and the Duckling, Golden Press, 1963.
Marion Borden, Stubby, Whitman, 1963.
Virginia Marshall, The Animals Playground, Wonder Books, 1964.
Lawrence Feigenbaum, This is a Newspaper, Follet Publishing Company, 1965.
Nan Gilbert, Hanna Barbera's Yogi Bear Takes a Vacation, Whitman, 1965.
Howard Garis, Uncle Wiggily Stories, Grosset & Dunlap, 1965.
Shannon Garst, The Picture Story and Biography of Red Cloud, Follett, 1965.
Joan P. Elwart, Animal Babies, Whitman, 1966.
Tom Glazer, On Top of Spaghett, Grosset & Dunlap, 1966.
Ken Sobol, Woodland Animals, McGraw-Hill, 1966.
Daphe Hogstrom, Paul Bunyan and Babe the Blue Ox, Whitman, 1967.
Solveig P. Russell, A White Sweater Must Be White, Grosset & Dunlap, 1967.
Edith G. Stull, The Turtle and the Roabbit, Singer, 1967.
Nathan Kravetz, The Dog on the Ice, Singer, 1968.
Ann McFerran, The Big and Little Book of ABC's, C.R. Gibson Co., 1969.
Lorrain Watters, The Magic of Music: Book One, Ginn and Co., 1970.
Mabel Watts, Merton and His Moving Van, Western Publishing Co., 1970.
Phyllis W. Goldman, Whatever Happened to Yes?, Walker, 1970.
Bob Ottum, The Airplane Book, Golden Press, 1972.
David L. Harrison, The Huffin Puff Express, Western Publishing Company, 1974.
Helen J. Fletcher, Fun with Puppies, Mulart, 1977.
Ilse M. Vogel, My Little Dinosaur, Western Publishing, 1979.
John Randolph, Fishing Basics, Prentice-Hall, 1981.
Lorna Slocombe, Sailing Basics, Prentice-Hall, 1982.
Patricia Romero, Tippet Shows Off Washington, Outdoor Books, 1983.
Ellen Schwartz, Ronald McDonald Alphabet, Kid Stuff, 1983.
Ellen Schwartz, Ronald McDonald One to Ten, Kid Stuff, 1983.
Edith Kunhardt, All Kinds of Trucks, Golden Book, 1984.
Lawrence Stevens, Computer Graphics Basics, Prentice-Hall, 1984.
Lawrence Stevens, Computer Programming Basics, Prentice-Hall, 1984.
Carl Laron, Electronics Basics, Prentice-Hall, 1984.
Lawrence Stevens, Laser Basics, Prentice-Hall, 1985.
Henry F. Halstead, Boating Basics, Prentice-Hall, 1985.
Mary Blocksma, Easy-to-Make Water Toys that Really Work, Prentice-Hall, 1985.
Carl Laron, Computer Software Basics, Prentice-Hall, 1985.
Bob Goldberg, Diving Basics, Prentice-Hall, 1986.
Rudy Kouhoupt, How on Earth do We Recycle Metal?, Millbrook Press, 1992.
Helen Fletcher, How on Earth do We Recycle Paper?, Millbrook Press, 1992.
Joanna Rott, How on Earth do We Recycle Glass?, Millbrook Press, 1992.
Barry Wilner, Soccer, Raintree Steck-Vaughn, 1993.
Lisa Harris, Hockey, Raintree Steck-Vaughn, 1994.
Bert Rosenthal, Track and Field, Raintree Steck-Vaughn, 1994.
Tom Withers, Basketball, Raintree Steck-Vaugh, 1994.
Dave Raffo, Football, Raintree Steck-Vaughn, 1994.
Mark Teirstein, Baseball, Raintree Steck-Vaughn, 1994.
Seymour Brody, Jewish Heroes and Heroines of America: 150 True Stories of American Jewish Heroism, Lifetime Books, 1996.
Barry Wilner, Swimming, Raintree Steck-Vaughn, 1996.
Thomas Nardi, Karate and Judo, Raintree Steck-Vaughn, 1996.
John Francis, Bicycling, Raintree Steck-Vaughn, 1996.
Margaret Wise Brown, The Train to Timbuctoo, Golden Books, 1999.
Scope and Content
Assorted pieces of original art by Art Seiden. Most pieces are matted, many have captions written on the artwork by the artist. No complete texts are represented.
Arrangement
Single series, one box.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to children's literature and associated artwork. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
Jewish Heroes and Heroines of America Dodd Call No. C5470
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Subjects:
Document Types:
Illustrations.; Books.
Occupations:
Illustrator.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
Donated to Archives & Special Collections by Art Seiden, through Norman Stevens.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Books, undated, 1950-1996
  - Jewish Heroes and Heroines of America, ca. 1996
    - 40 line drawings, ca. 1996 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - The Animal's Playground
    - One matted piece, 1964 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Book of Puzzles
    - One matted piece - (Cover Art), ca. 1967
  - Myths and Legends - Gods and Heroes
    - 3 pieces original art (2 are matted), 1960 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - 1-2-3 Board Book
    - One piece original art (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - One piece slide presentation art - Walworth Valves, undated
  - One piece art design for greeting card, undated
  - One piece original art (matted) unused endpaper design, undated
  - The Little Engine that Laughed
    - 4 pieces matted original art (includes cover art), 1950 (Box 1:, Folder 5)